<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.speakoutnews.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.speakoutnews.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-10-10T11:21:44-05:00</updated><id>https://www.speakoutnews.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Speak Out</title><subtitle>We are here to speak truth to power and hold politicians accountable for their actions and policies. We seek true justice, equality, and love.</subtitle><author><name>Contact Us</name><email>speakoutnewsroom@gmail.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">The Irony of Charlie Kirk’s Death - Part 2</title><link href="https://www.speakoutnews.com/2025/09/24/the-irony-of-charlie-kirks-death-part-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Irony of Charlie Kirk’s Death - Part 2" /><published>2025-09-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-09-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.speakoutnews.com/2025/09/24/the-irony-of-charlie-kirks-death-part-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.speakoutnews.com/2025/09/24/the-irony-of-charlie-kirks-death-part-2.html"><![CDATA[<p>Of course, the other great irony of Charlie Kirk’s death is the maelstrom surrounding it regarding Freedom of Speech. In life, Kirk advocated for it, even in some of its most extreme forms, of which he was a practitioner. In death, Trump and Kirk’s other allies have jettisoned the right to free expression, and in fact have used that death to suppress free expression by everyone from <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cr4qe0rz2zvo">Jimmy Kimmel</a> to the <a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/americas/us-politics/washington-post-fired-charlie-kirk-karen-attiah-b2826734.html">Washington Post</a>.</p>

<p>Just as the Trump Administration is using American Jews to <a href="https://www.npr.org/2025/09/17/nx-s1-5543212/study-most-american-jews-dont-agree-with-trumps-tactics-for-combating-antisemitism">justify repression of American Universities</a> which Trump claims are not adequately protecting them, it is now using Kirk’s death to justify Stalinist attacks on media and the press. Like all autocrats, Trump needs to control the press so that his propaganda is all Americans hear and read.</p>

<p>In law, where many areas are gray, the scope of the First Amendment is remarkably clear. The right to free speech is not absolute. Shouting “fire” in a crowded movie theater is not protected, nor is defamatory speech, or the dissemination of state secrets regarding our mutual defense. “Fighting words” are not protected, that is, words that would provoke an immediate, violent response. The government has the right to reasonably regulate the time, place, and manner of speech. (Afterall, if we are all shouting at the same time and place, no one can be heard. For that reason, the government can license the airwaves). But that’s about it. Other speech, no matter how cruel, unfair, illogical, crude, crass, or in bad taste, is sacrosanct. (See <a href="https://supreme.justia.com/cases-by-topic/free-speech/">Free Speech Supreme Court Cases</a>.) Americans get this, which is why ABC <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/jimmy-kimmel-returns-late-night-television-six-day-suspension-2025-09-23/">restored Kimmel to the airwaves</a> so quickly.</p>

<p>To paraphrase the film, <em>The American President</em>, we have to defend our fellow citizens’ right to speech that would make our own blood boil. So, to my knowledge, the organized Left never made any attempt to silence the racist, antisemitic, transphobic, and misogynistic speech of Charlie Kirk. But surely we are not obligated to lionize him in death, and in fact have every right to criticize him posthumously. Frankly, I am not sure that doing so furthers our cause, but that is for “the marketplace of ideas” to decide.</p>

<p>I do want to correct the record on one point. In the haze of Kirk’s death, commentators have claimed that he exercised his First Amendment rights <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/11/opinion/charlie-kirk-assassination-fear-politics.html">“the right way,”</a> by open debate with those he opposed. Let’s not delude ourselves. Kirk had the megaphone, which he gripped tightly. He did not share it, entertain opposing views, or fairly debate his worldview. He took advantage of, and no doubt <a href="https://www.erininthemorning.com/p/we-must-not-posthumously-sanitize">worsened the cultural divide</a> in this country by remaining ensconced in the Right’s media ecosphere. What we need, and what we should welcome, would be leaders who bridge the gap between the two sides. And that, Charlie Kirk never attempted in any real way.</p>]]></content><author><name>Jekyll Esq</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Of course, the other great irony of Charlie Kirk’s death is the maelstrom surrounding it regarding Freedom of Speech. In life, Kirk advocated for it, even in some of its most extreme forms, of which he was a practitioner. In death, Trump and Kirk’s other allies have jettisoned the right to free expression, and in fact have used that death to suppress free expression by everyone from Jimmy Kimmel to the Washington Post.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Irony of Charlie Kirk’s Death - Part 1</title><link href="https://www.speakoutnews.com/2025/09/24/the-irony-of-charlie-kirks-death-part-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Irony of Charlie Kirk’s Death - Part 1" /><published>2025-09-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-09-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.speakoutnews.com/2025/09/24/the-irony-of-charlie-kirks-death-part-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.speakoutnews.com/2025/09/24/the-irony-of-charlie-kirks-death-part-1.html"><![CDATA[<p>Here at <em>Speak Out</em>, we don’t believe that anyone should be a victim of gun violence, a stance Charlie Kirk, may he rest, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rMzr5cDKza0">publicly and professionally opposed</a>.  Charlie was right that senseless gun violence is the trade-off we as a society make when we promote a limitless proliferation of guns and weapons in our society.  He thought the trade-off was worth the cost.  But we at <em>Speak Out</em> do not.</p>

<p>Charlie Kirk did not respect the life or dignity of others unlike himself.  He <a href="https://www.snopes.com/fact-check/charlie-kirk-called-kyle-rittenhouse-a-hero/">celebrated the deaths</a> of Joseph Rosenbaum and Anthony Huber at the hands of Kyle Rittenhouse.  He often <a href="https://www.advocate.com/politics/charlie-kirk-anti-lgbtq-quotes#rebelltitem2">called for the death of queer people</a>.  He <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@alexgproductions/video/7551580347893304631">mocked those who sought to end the genocide in Gaza</a>.  He believed that the Civil Rights Act was a <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/charlie-kirk-tpusa-mlk-civil-rights-act/">“huge mistake”</a> and that <a href="https://www.snopes.com/fact-check/charlie-kirk-black-women/">women of color are mentally inferior to white men</a>.  To Charlie, empathy itself was <a href="https://www.snopes.com/fact-check/charlie-kirk-empathy-quote/">a dangerous idea</a>.</p>

<p>If Charlie Kirk had not been a Christian, conservative, straight, cisgender, white man, Charlie himself would not have thought him worthy of a dignified life.  So it is up to us on the left to once again take up that dangerous ideology of empathy and acceptance, and proclaim that <em>all</em> people, of all walks of life, deserve to live healthy, dignified lives (even those of bigots like Charlie).  We even ask for compassion in sparing the life of his alleged killer, who may well face the <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/live/c04qenww53pt">death penalty</a> (just another form of violence Charlie was all too happy to <a href="https://www.snopes.com/news/2025/09/15/charlie-kirk-public-executions/">endorse</a>).  But we will also never give an inch to the hateful and harmful ideas Charlie Kirk and his fellow far-right conservatives espouse.  And we will continue to demand meaningful gun reform.</p>

<p>To those who ask that we mourn Charlie’s death and honor his life (overwhelmingly from the right, but also some prominent personalities on the left as well: <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/11/opinion/charlie-kirk-assassination-fear-politics.html"><em>e.g.</em>, Ezra Klein</a>), you ask an impossible task.  To honor his life would be to dismiss the circumstances of his death.  To mourn his death would require acknowledging the atrocities we invite upon school children so men like Charlie can think themselves big and strong while hiding behind a gun.</p>

<p>Instead, we renounce the bigotry he promoted in life.  But of his death, we see only the needless lost of another life.</p>]]></content><author><name>Mx Hyde</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here at Speak Out, we don’t believe that anyone should be a victim of gun violence, a stance Charlie Kirk, may he rest, publicly and professionally opposed. Charlie was right that senseless gun violence is the trade-off we as a society make when we promote a limitless proliferation of guns and weapons in our society. He thought the trade-off was worth the cost. But we at Speak Out do not.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">It Doesn’t Matter When a Fetus Becomes a Person</title><link href="https://www.speakoutnews.com/2025/06/25/it-doesnt-matter-when-a-fetus-becomes-a-person.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="It Doesn’t Matter When a Fetus Becomes a Person" /><published>2025-06-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-06-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.speakoutnews.com/2025/06/25/it-doesnt-matter-when-a-fetus-becomes-a-person</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.speakoutnews.com/2025/06/25/it-doesnt-matter-when-a-fetus-becomes-a-person.html"><![CDATA[<p>An often debated question around the right to abortion and reproductive healthcare is that of fetal personhood, <em>i.e.</em>, when does a fetus become a person, entitled to the legal protections enjoyed by all non-fetus people?  It is a central tenant in the pro-life stance of most religious people and organizations: <a href="https://catholic.duke.edu/why-are-catholics-pro-life/">life begins at conception, and therefore that life must be protected</a>.  Even the original <em>Roe v. Wade</em> decision of the Supreme Court, which protected access to abortion early in a pregnancy, but did allow for states to restrict abortion access later in the pregnancy, <a href="https://tile.loc.gov/storage-services/service/ll/usrep/usrep410/usrep410113/usrep410113.pdf">based its decision on the principle that fetal life needs regulatory protection even if it infringes on the bodily autonomy of the pregnant person</a>.  It’s such a common argument in favor of abortion restrictions, that many seem to take it as fact that the question of when abortions go from permitted to prohibited is <em>precisely</em> when a fetus becomes a person.</p>

<p>But does this argument hold water?  No, it does not.  And it’s not that life and consciousness are too difficult to measure or philosophically imprecise, it’s that even if full personhood is granted to a fetus at the moment of conception, full and unhindered access to abortions at <em>any</em> stage in a pregnancy should still be an uncontroversial and protected right.</p>

<p>From a legal perspective, in no other case is the state given the power to take one person’s body, in whole or in part, to sustain the life of another.</p>

<p>Even in the case where a person harms another, or gives birth to a child, the state cannot compel such actions.  The at-fault driver of a car accident cannot be compelled to donate blood to save the life of victim of their negligent driving.  A parent cannot be compelled to donate a kidney to their own child.  This situation is exactly analogous to that of an abortion: where the fetus is considered a living child with personhood, but they need a parent’s uterus or kidney or liver or any other organ to survive.  And yet still, the state cannot compel such an organ donation after the child is born, so why would the state be able to force such a donation before the child is born?  Views on the morality of refusing such help may differ, just as personal views on the morality of abortions under certain circumstances will still exist.  But legally, it is a decided matter that <a href="https://hulr.org/spring-2021/mcfall-v-shimp-and-the-case-for-bodily-autonomy">no circumstance, even one of life or death, grants the state power over bodily integrity to provide nourishment or care for another</a>.</p>

<p>When those of us who are pro-choice, and understand the importance of abortion and healthcare access, find ourselves in arguments with pro-lifers, we need to stop getting bogged down in the philosophical debate of when life begins, grant for the sake of argument fetal personhood, and move on to why that doesn’t matter.  If the state cannot compel organ donations, well then that’s sort of the end of the discussion, the state cannot compel the donation of a uterus, even to support the life of another person.</p>]]></content><author><name>Mx Hyde</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[An often debated question around the right to abortion and reproductive healthcare is that of fetal personhood, i.e., when does a fetus become a person, entitled to the legal protections enjoyed by all non-fetus people? It is a central tenant in the pro-life stance of most religious people and organizations: life begins at conception, and therefore that life must be protected. Even the original Roe v. Wade decision of the Supreme Court, which protected access to abortion early in a pregnancy, but did allow for states to restrict abortion access later in the pregnancy, based its decision on the principle that fetal life needs regulatory protection even if it infringes on the bodily autonomy of the pregnant person. It’s such a common argument in favor of abortion restrictions, that many seem to take it as fact that the question of when abortions go from permitted to prohibited is precisely when a fetus becomes a person.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why I Vote (and you should too)</title><link href="https://www.speakoutnews.com/2025/02/21/why-i-vote.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why I Vote (and you should too)" /><published>2025-02-21T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2025-02-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://www.speakoutnews.com/2025/02/21/why-i-vote</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.speakoutnews.com/2025/02/21/why-i-vote.html"><![CDATA[<p>Many people do not vote because they believe prominent politicians will not champion the kinds of radical change we desire of them.  Our societal systems <em>do</em> need to change radically, and voting, for example for Democrats, will not bring about those needed radical and systemic changes; however, not voting is also equally as ineffective as voting in that regard.  Even if only 20M people vote in the next presidential election (down from ~150M in recent presidential elections), which would undoubtedly be the greatest drop in voter turnout ever, I don’t think that would take away any of the legitimacy of the election, at least not in any way that really matters.  In almost every major race, either a Democrat or a Republican will still be sworn in and receive the keys to power.  I believe that governments fall/change when the vast majority of people actively reject the right of that particular government to rule.  And low-to-no voter turnout is a result of that rejection, not the cause of it.  As long as most Americans believe in the institutions of government, they will accept the authority of the winner even if voter turnout is absurdly low.  The types of actions required to bring about radical, systemic change do not happen at the ballot box.  But nothing about voting precludes you from engaging in those revolutionary actions.  In the meantime, the current system of government still exists and still has real, meaningful impacts on every single person (certainly in this country, but arguably even the whole world).  It is worth engaging in harm reduction within the system even while simultaneously working to radically change it from without.</p>]]></content><author><name>Mx Hyde</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Many people do not vote because they believe prominent politicians will not champion the kinds of radical change we desire of them. Our societal systems do need to change radically, and voting, for example for Democrats, will not bring about those needed radical and systemic changes; however, not voting is also equally as ineffective as voting in that regard. Even if only 20M people vote in the next presidential election (down from ~150M in recent presidential elections), which would undoubtedly be the greatest drop in voter turnout ever, I don’t think that would take away any of the legitimacy of the election, at least not in any way that really matters. In almost every major race, either a Democrat or a Republican will still be sworn in and receive the keys to power. I believe that governments fall/change when the vast majority of people actively reject the right of that particular government to rule. And low-to-no voter turnout is a result of that rejection, not the cause of it. As long as most Americans believe in the institutions of government, they will accept the authority of the winner even if voter turnout is absurdly low. The types of actions required to bring about radical, systemic change do not happen at the ballot box. But nothing about voting precludes you from engaging in those revolutionary actions. In the meantime, the current system of government still exists and still has real, meaningful impacts on every single person (certainly in this country, but arguably even the whole world). It is worth engaging in harm reduction within the system even while simultaneously working to radically change it from without.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Art of the Con</title><link href="https://www.speakoutnews.com/2025/02/14/the-art-of-the-con.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Art of the Con" /><published>2025-02-14T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2025-02-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://www.speakoutnews.com/2025/02/14/the-art-of-the-con</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.speakoutnews.com/2025/02/14/the-art-of-the-con.html"><![CDATA[<p>(Spoiler alert: This article gives away plot twists and endings of <em>The Music Man</em>; <em>The Sting</em>; <em>Dirty, Rotten Scoundrels</em>; and <em>House of Games</em>).</p>

<p>Everyone recognizes the con artist archetype in American cinema and culture. From Professor Harold Hill (played by Robert Preston) in <em>The Music Man,</em> to Henry Gondorff (Paul Newman) and Johnny Hooker (Robert Redford) in <em>The Sting,</em> this character is usually an iconoclastic rogue beating the system with cunning and guile. We root for these con men (and occasionally women), even though they draw innocent “marks” into their confidence (thus the name), in order to fleece them. Sometimes their cons appear harmless. In <em>The Music Man,</em> Hill convinces the townsfolk that there’s trouble in River City, that starts with “T” and rhymes with “P,” which stands for pool. The only way to protect the town’s youth from exposure to pool halls is by forming a marching band. The citizens happily give Hill their money to buy band uniforms and instruments, even though neither are to be had. In the film’s ending, uniforms and instruments magically appear, and equally as magical, the kids know how to play them. It is all harmless fun, where no one ends up getting hurt.</p>

<p>In other con-artist tales, the marks who get swindled are very bad people who get what’s coming to them. At the beginning of <em>The Sting,</em> Hooker and his partner Luther perpetrate a short con unknowingly on a bag man for a mobster. They give the man money (or at least he thinks they’ve given him money) to deliver to its rightful owner. But we learn that the bag man takes off in a cab in the opposite direction than the rightful owner. So, they’ve conned an immoral person. Then, Gondorff and Hooker set up the elaborate long con of the mobster himself, Doyle Lonnegan, who oversees a large, criminal enterprise, and casually orders Luther’s murder. As in many of these American myths, the film is a morality play in which the con artists, employing unconventional and even illegal means, exact justice against victims who are the actual evil-doers. Again, good folks don’t get hurt.</p>

<p>Of course, real con artists have practiced their art on real, flesh-and-blood victims throughout American history. On the frontier they sold snake oil. In the twentieth century, they sold swampland in Florida, and later junk bonds. On the internet they range from the Nigerian Prince asking that you hold their funds in exchange for a handsome fee, to all manner of phishing practitioners. Rather than loveable rogues, they are predators preying on people’s greed, yes, but also on their gullibility or innocence.</p>

<p>Out of this rich history of con artists, both of movie heroes and their ignominious real life counterparts, comes the greatest grifter of all-time: Donald J. Trump. His begins with a completely fabricated origin story. In his telling, upon Donald’s coming-of-age, his father, a fabulously wealthy developer, gives him a “modest” stake of <a href="https://www.today.com/news/donald-trump-my-dad-gave-me-small-loan-1-million-t52166">$1 million</a>. Let’s set aside for a moment that for most of us, a million bucks is an enormous amount of money that we could only wish we’d received when setting out in the world. The more important point is that the story is simply a lie. According to the 2018 <em>New York Times</em> expose by Pulitzer Prize winning journalists Susanne Craig and Russ Buettner, Trump’s dad gave him <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2018/10/02/us/politics/donald-trump-tax-schemes-fred-trump.html">in excess of $400 million</a> over time to prop up Trump’s failing business ventures or rescue Trump from financial ruin. As detailed in Craig and Buettner’s book, <em>Lucky Loser,</em> virtually every business Trump touched turned to shit (a sort of Midas-touch in reverse). Even after <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/donald-trumps-business-plan-left-a-trail-of-unpaid-bills-1465504454">systematically stiffing his contractors and employees</a>, Trump could not even make a go of running casinos (the ownership of which is generally likened to a license to print money), running <a href="https://www.thoughtco.com/donald-trump-business-bankruptcies-4152019">several of them into bankruptcy</a>. Over time, his so-called empire was built on a mountain of debt, requiring that he be bailed out by daddy, or other creditors. As just one example of his lack of business acumen, Trump bluffed his way into purchasing a team in the upstart United States Football League (USFL), using purely borrowed money. He then bullied his fellow owners into a series of awful decisions, such as moving the spring schedule to the fall, and into direct competition with the NFL. Almost singularly <a href="https://www.esquire.com/news-politics/a41135/donald-trump-usfl/">due to Trump’s bad judgment, the USFL collapsed</a> in short order. His grifts have run far and wide, from Trump University to Trump Steaks. His first presidential campaign and inaugural were set up as grifts to profit Trump.</p>

<p>Somehow through it all, Trump sold the big con that he was a great businessman. The truth is that since the building of Trump Tower, one of his only true accomplishments, his greatest source of wealth has been <em>The Apprentice,</em> a television show in which he ironically played an enormously successful businessman. As Craig and Buettner explain, the producers of the show <a href="https://screenrant.com/the-apprentice-exec-reveals-if-he-created-a-monster-with-donald-trump/">first approached a number of actual titans of business, all of whom demurred</a>. They finally got to the bottom of the barrel with you-know-who. When they went to meet The Donald at his offices in Trump Tower, they were shocked to see a barely staffed workplace, with shabby and worn furnishings. The offices were so pitiful that the producers had to build a TV set of “the boardroom” that was used on the show. Utilizing all the magic of show business, they created the illusion of a successful business tycoon. After Trump’s election, at least <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/10/18/business/video/trump-apprentice-executive-apology-digvid">one of the show’s creators lamented having created this mythological figure</a> who rode that fiction all the way to the White House.</p>

<p>To be successful, almost all movies in the con-artist genre have to do more than tell the con artist’s story. In some way they need to <em>con the audience itself</em>. In <em>The Sting,</em> we believe that Hooker has sold out Gondorff to the Feds, and that they both get shot in the climax. Only at the very end do we learn that we too have been conned, and we love it. In <em>Dirty, Rotten Scoundrels,</em> (inspired by the classic <em>To Catch a Thief</em>) Michael Caine and Steve Martin play con men on the Riviera competing to swindle a gullible heiress out of her fortune. At the end we learn that she is the actual con artist, who has conned the con men (and of course the audience). Again, no one really gets hurt; Caine and Martin get their comeuppance. Throughout David Mamet’s <em>House of Games,</em> we think we are watching Mike (Joe Mantegna) teach a psychologist (Lindsay Crouse) about the short con, such as convincing someone waiting at a Western Union office to give away money being wired to him. Ultimately we learn that yet again we have been the mark; the whole movie is actually a long-con on the psychologist.</p>

<p>All of which brings me to the point: Liberals have for years shaken their heads in disbelief,  wondering how Trump could have conned his supporters. How could they be fooled into believing that he was a great businessman? That he knew how to run our government? That he cared anything at all about their problems, let alone do anything to solve them? That he wasn’t using the presidency merely as a vehicle to line his own pockets with scores of new grifts? (Can I sell you some Trump action figures or cryptocurrency?!) And after the utter disaster of his first term, his impeachments, criminal prosecutions and his felony conviction, how could even more of them vote him back for a second? Apparently the adage of “fool me once…” has no application. Democrats have surmised that those conned simply refuse to admit, maybe even to themselves, that they’ve been had by the ultimate charlatan.</p>

<p>Well, the Left has it all wrong. Here’s the plot twist: A very large portion of Trumpers <em>know full well that he is a grifter, and that they are being conned!</em> They simply don’t care. To them, he is one of those loveable rogues we see in the movies. And in his own deceptive and often criminal way, he is sticking it to the real bad guys, who in their eyes are the liberal elites. In fact, some even enjoy being conned, just like the audiences watching those movies where the viewers themselves are the ones being fooled. And so really the Left was the true mark of the long con the whole time, tricked into thinking Trump’s supporters were being bamboozled when in reality they openly embrace his schemes to win the culture war they want so badly. The tragedy, of course, is that Trump is not a celluloid con artist. He is one of those very real ones, who cause very real harm to very real people. Now he is back on the stage where he can inflict maximum damage. When this horror movie finally ends, we cannot simply get up and leave the theater. We will have to live with the catastrophic and long-lasting results.</p>]]></content><author><name>Jekyll Esq</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[(Spoiler alert: This article gives away plot twists and endings of The Music Man; The Sting; Dirty, Rotten Scoundrels; and House of Games).]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Biological sex is also a social construct</title><link href="https://www.speakoutnews.com/2025/02/12/biological-sex-is-also-a-social-construct.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Biological sex is also a social construct" /><published>2025-02-12T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2025-02-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://www.speakoutnews.com/2025/02/12/biological-sex-is-also-a-social-construct</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.speakoutnews.com/2025/02/12/biological-sex-is-also-a-social-construct.html"><![CDATA[<p>Gender is a social construct; sex is biology.  It’s a common way of explaining the difference between sex and gender.  And it places the concept of <em>biological sex</em> into the realm of concrete, scientific fact.  There are two main problems with this notion of biological sex: it’s messy and it’s arbitrary.</p>

<p>The appeal to biological sex (as opposed to gender) is often made to reintroduce a fixed, binary classification of people by claiming some underlying scientific reality.  The Trump Administration is using this exact argument <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/01/defending-women-from-gender-ideology-extremism-and-restoring-biological-truth-to-the-federal-government/">to claim that there are only two sexes, which are biologically distinct</a> in an infallible and objective way.  The problem with this line of reasoning is that biological sex is messy.  Extremely messy actually.</p>

<p>One recent attempt to establish a fixed binary is to define sex through sex chromosomes.  Namely, women have an XX sex karyotype (<em>i.e.</em>, an individual’s specific collection of chromosomes) and men XY.  For starters, <a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC1634840/">there are many more possible karyotypes besides XX and XY</a>, including (but not limited to) X, XXY, XYY, XXX, XXYY, and XXXY.</p>

<p>An attempt to resolve the chromosome karyotype problem is to instead define male and female as the presence or absence, respectively, of the Y chromosome.  So XY male and XX female, but also XXY and XYY male while X and XXX female, for instance.  The motivation for this classification system being that the gene which causes most traditional “masculine” development, the <a href="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/gene/sry/">SRY gene</a>, is (usually) located on the Y chromosome and (usually) absent on the X chromosome.  But of course, this new system is far from perfect.  The SRY gene i<a href="https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/swyer-syndrome/#causes">sn’t always present on the Y chromosome or may code for a non-functional protein</a>.  Alternatively, the SRY gene can sometimes be <a href="https://ui.adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/1986Sci...233..786A/abstract">present on the X chromosome</a>.  And the expression of genes in general exists not as a binary, but on a <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/hdy201054">continuum controlled by epigenetic processes</a>.</p>

<p>And of course there’s the chronological issue of our concept of biological sex <a href="https://www.etymonline.com/word/sex">predating</a> any <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20210421055737/https://www.zin.ru/journals/protistology/num8_1/fokin_protistology_8-1.pdf">knowledge or understanding of chromosomes or genes</a> by a very large margin.  To accept the chromosomal or genetic definition of sex is to then argue that no such concept of sex or the sexes existed before 1848.</p>

<p>Another proposed classification system looks at gonads and gametes.  Do you have ovaries or testes, producing ova or sperm cells?  This is the route taken in Trump’s recent <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/01/defending-women-from-gender-ideology-extremism-and-restoring-biological-truth-to-the-federal-government/">EO</a>.  It is also fraught with ambiguity.  Not only can people have <a href="https://rarediseases.org/rare-diseases/ovotesticular-disorder-of-sex-development/">both</a> organs at birth, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/medgen/899272">neither</a>, or <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/medgen/78601">ambiguous</a> gonads, but these organs also develop over a lifetime and can be removed.  For all its flaws, at least chromosomes are (mutations and meiosis aside) set at conception and fixed for our lifetimes.  Are children sexless until puberty or adults sexless after menopause?  Can a simple surgery or injury change your biological sex?  The gonad/gamete classification system is ill-equipped to handle such questions.  And the attempt to resolve these shortcomings by defining sex by the gonads at any particular time (such as at conception) is not useful because the development or loss of these organs is not the same for every individual.</p>

<p>A more traditional classification method might simply refer to the shape of a person’s genitals.  Many of the same problems exist here too.  Genitals actually exist on a spectrum and it <a href="https://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/ambiguous-genitalia/symptoms-causes/syc-20369273">isn’t always unambiguous</a> whether a person clearly has a penis or a vulva.  But also like gonads, these organs change and develop with time.  They can be altered or removed, intentionally or from an accident.</p>

<p>Hormone levels are also often considered an aspect of biological sex.  The distributions of androgens, estrogens, and other sex hormones tend to be bimodal in people.  But of course that means there is plenty of overlap.  Not every otherwise seemingly unambiguous <a href="https://my.clevelandclinic.org/health/diseases/15603-low-testosterone-male-hypogonadism">cis man has higher testosterone levels</a> than every otherwise seemingly unambiguous <a href="https://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJM199410133311502">cis woman</a>.  Hormones change daily <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1002/j.1939-4640.1999.tb03378.x">based on our circadian rhythms</a>, during menstrual cycles, and of course greatly <a href="https://medlineplus.gov/ency/article/004000.htm">over the course of our lifetimes</a> as we go through puberty and then into adulthood and finally old age.  Things like <a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC8489575/">diet and exercise</a> can significantly change sex hormone balances.  And of course many medications can alter these levels.  Furthermore, <a href="https://my.clevelandclinic.org/health/diseases/22199-androgen-insensitivity-syndrome">sensitivity to the various sex hormones can vary greatly</a> between individuals.  Of all the classification systems, the hormone level definition is the most nebulous, far too varied to be determinative of any underlying innate trait.</p>

<p>All the ambiguity around sex classification means that <em>many</em> people do not fit cleanly into a traditional sense of male or female. The percentage of intersex people has been estimated to be <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11534012/">as high as 2%</a>.  That would be over 150 million people worldwide: more than the entire populations of Canada, Colombia, and Cambodia combined!  You could have intersex traits and not even know it.  Most people will never have their chromosomes tested.  Unless you are trying to have children and seeking infertility care, you likely will not ever have your gonads or gametes studied.  And it’s not as though blood tests for hormone levels are part of every routine physical.  There’s a reason why many cisgender athletes <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2016/07/03/magazine/the-humiliating-practice-of-sex-testing-female-athletes.html">don’t know they exhibit certain intersex traits</a> until they are forced to submit to a sex verification test, a time-honored tradition as old as <a href="https://www.heraldscotland.com/news/12368031.Helen_Stephens___Hitler_pinched_my_bottom/">Hitler groping a woman</a> during the Berlin Olympics in 1936.</p>

<p>And to be clear, it is not intersex people who have failed to be biological by existing, but instead their existence which shows that the concept of biological sex is fundamentally flawed.  Their experiences and their biological traits are just as real and valid as anyone else’s.  It is the insistence on a binary classification which causes people equally as deserving of dignity and respect to be dehumanized and disregarded.</p>

<p>Diving into the nuances of any purported scientific definition of sex misses the point though,  and in many ways legitimizes the attempts to <em>enforce</em> such a rigid binary.  By going through all the flaws of the currently proposed definitions, I am not conceding that if a clean classification system were to exist, then its use in our society would be warranted.  Of course it is not.  And that failure is because of the arbitrariness of the mere concept of biological sex.</p>

<p>Even though a trait is measurable does not mean it has to hold any importance in our society.  Even if it is true that, at any given time, many of the above traits do exist and are quantifiable, that has no bearing on how we as a society decide to act on them.  And placing an over importance on these traits is to commit the McNamara Fallacy.</p>

<p>Consider a US Passport.  If you haven’t looked at one in a while, you might be surprised to realize how few demographics are printed on it.  It does not include height, weight, hair or eye color.  The only auxiliary piece of information is sex.  Why include this information and not height?  Or femur length?  Or the circumference of your left pinky at the second knuckle?  All of these are measurable.  All are “facts” of our biology.  Any could be part of a process of identification.  But we don’t include the circumference of our left pinky at the second knuckle on government documents or segregate our sports teams by this metric.  It is not as though the Customs agent is testing your chromosomes or doing a blood test to measure your hormone levels at the airport.  If anything, measuring your pinky would be a much easier and more clearly defined task.</p>

<p>We do not merely put sex designations on all our documents and use them to dictate societal behaviors; we have also decided that this classification is not allowed to change.  Consider the Driver’s License, which actually does have other identifying information on it such as hair color and corrective lens necessity.  Even though these other metrics are still arbitrary, our society at least accepts that they can change, both naturally and artificially.  We don’t consider it a crisis of society or biology when a person dyes their hair or grows 3 inches.  We do not seek to ban color-changing contact lenses because it might mean a person born with blue eyes could pass as having brown eyes.  Thus, not only is biological sex an arbitrary classification system, but even among arbitrary classification systems, biological sex is even more arbitrary, as it alone is considered truly innate and eternal.</p>

<p>Finally, no one is entitled to know every fact about another person.  There are many facts about ourselves and our lives that we choose to, and are entitled to, keep private.  Take our reproductive organs as an example.  Sure, they do have a factually accurate appearance at any given time.  But that does not mean other people are entitled to know what that appearance is.  We pick with whom to share that information, often just our intimate partners and maybe a doctor.  It’s one of the reasons why the insistence by bigots that people reveal their “true” sex is often such an uncomfortable act.  They appeal to “facts” as cover to justify their demands for a detailed description of another’s genitals or the results of a sensitive lab test.  No one has a right to that information just because it’s measurable or factual.  And many do not wish to be defined solely on the basis of these personal and intimate attributes.</p>

<p>In closing, consider a hypothetical society which also classifies people by a purported biologically grounded, binary trait.  A trait which is mostly controlled by genetics and which can be scientifically measured.  Imagine a world where our government documents have either a D or a W on them for the two different <a href="https://www.23andme.com/topics/traits/earwax-type/">earwax types</a>: dry or wet, respectively.  In this world, dry-earwax-havers tend to pursue careers in STEM fields, cut their hair short, wear suits, and don’t wear makeup.  The wet-earwax-havers, in contrast, often have careers in hospitality, keep their hair long, and wear dresses and makeup.  We have separate bathrooms, separate locker rooms, sometimes even separate schools, for the dry vs wet earwax-havers.  And of course hotly debated issues in this society include whether we need to take political action to get rid of any medication that might alter the moisture content of a person’s earwax.  Q-tips and cotton swabs are heavily regulated due to their ability to obscure or change a person’s earwax type.  And while people of this society do have the freedom to dress as they choose, or marry whomever they fancy, it’s often considered “unnatural” if they deviate from societal norms around earwax wetness.  And any attempt to support a child who doesn’t wish to be constrained by their earwax type, or even teaching them the real science (or lack thereof) behind earwax types, is considered an act of child abuse.</p>

<p>Is there any way in which this hypothetical society is fundamentally different from our own?  The fact that we chose to care about reproductive organs and hormone levels instead of earwax type and moisture levels is proof alone that biological sex is an arbitrary social construct.</p>]]></content><author><name>Mx Hyde</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gender is a social construct; sex is biology. It’s a common way of explaining the difference between sex and gender. And it places the concept of biological sex into the realm of concrete, scientific fact. There are two main problems with this notion of biological sex: it’s messy and it’s arbitrary.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Racism, the one thing holding MAGA together</title><link href="https://www.speakoutnews.com/2025/02/02/racism-the-one-thing-holding-maga-together.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Racism, the one thing holding MAGA together" /><published>2025-02-02T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2025-02-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://www.speakoutnews.com/2025/02/02/racism-the-one-thing-holding-maga-together</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.speakoutnews.com/2025/02/02/racism-the-one-thing-holding-maga-together.html"><![CDATA[<p>The MAGA movement remains stubbornly resistant to definition or characterization. Other than cult-like fealty to its leader, Donald Trump, the movement appears to have no consistent, unifying principles. It is isolationist, but open to <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/dec/29/trump-greenland-panama-china-threats">invading Canada, Mexico, Panama, and, for goodness sake, Greenland</a>. Many of its adherents are Evangelical Christians, and yet they have deified a relentlessly corrupt and immoral sociopath as their Orange Jesus. The movement aspires to a type of rugged individualism, but has no problem <a href="https://apnews.com/article/trump-hannity-dictator-authoritarian-presidential-election-f27e7e9d7c13fabbe3ae7dd7f1235c72">jettisoning democracy for autocracy</a>. Its roots are rural, but it is fine with the imposition of <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us-farmers-back-trump-face-pain-china-tariff-threats-2024-11-07/">tariffs which will decimate the American farmer</a>. MAGA fears and distrusts big tech, and yet its new oligarchy is comprised of Musk, Bezos, Zuckerberg and other tech bros. And it celebrates anti-elitism, while worshipping a leader who literally shits on a toilet made of gold.</p>

<p>The one through-line of MAGA world is an undercurrent of white grievance fueled by unabashed racism. Today, the entire Republican Party is beholden to White Nationalism. How did we get here?</p>

<p>For generations following the Civil War, the Party of Lincoln and of the Emancipation Proclamation was the one hospitable to African Americans. <a href="https://las.illinois.edu/news/2020-12-09/dynamic-history-black-voters">Frederick Douglass is reported to have once</a> said, “The Republican Party is the ship; all else is the sea.” It was the Republicans who would shepherd through the Fifteenth Amendment theoretically guaranteeing the access of all black (men) to the ballot box.  And for nearly a century, the South was reliably Democratic. <a href="https://www.npr.org/transcripts/331298996">The migration of black voters from the Republicans to the Democrats began in the 1930s</a>. Black voters appreciated that FDR brought people of color into his administration, and moreover that the social safety net he created to blunt the ravages of the Great Depression, extended, in theory, to <em>all</em> struggling Americans. (It is important to note that many federal policies under FDR were still very discriminatory. One example was the practice of <a href="https://a816-dohbesp.nyc.gov/IndicatorPublic/data-stories/redlining/">denying black homeowners the same access to funds to avoid foreclosures that were offered to white homeowners.</a> Even the original Social Security Act <a href="https://naacp.org/articles/viewing-social-security-through-civil-rights-lens">failed to cover over 65% of black American workers</a>.) However, as recently as the 1950s, <a href="https://www.npr.org/transcripts/331298996">roughly one-third of black voters were Republicans</a>. The seismic change did not really take hold until the 1960s. By then, the Democratic Party had become far more welcoming to African Americans. Even after <a href="https://www.jfklibrary.org/learn/about-jfk/jfk-in-history/civil-rights-movement">JFK used federal resources to enforce desegregation in the South</a>, the Blue Dogs remained loyal to the Democratic Party.</p>

<p>I would suggest that racist white voters remained Democrats for decades because until the mid-60s, the black vote remained inconsequential, particularly in the South. When Reconstruction collapsed following the Civil War, white leaders enforced a brutal regime of Jim Crow disenfranchisement, including poll taxes, literacy tests, and all manner of voter intimidation. Subsequent Democratic inroads into the African American community were not particularly concerning to white southerners, because so few black southerners were able to vote. As such, they possessed no real electoral power.</p>

<p>All that changed during the Civil Rights movement, and particularly with the passage of the Voting Rights Act of 1965. The effects were dramatic and virtually immediate. Within a year of its passage, the percentage of black citizens of Alabama who were registered to vote jumped from <a href="https://publicwise.org/publication/black-enfranchisement-after-the-voting-rights-act/">11% to 51%. In Tennessee, those numbers grew from 27% to 72%</a>. White southerners must have been terrified that the group of people they had so effectively kept down for 100 years would suddenly have some political power to affect change.</p>

<p>In the post-war 1940s and ‘50s, the Republican Party was largely comprised of “Rockefeller Republicans.” These were the true elites. They went to the best schools, held the best-paying jobs, and lived in the most desirable neighborhoods. The problem was that there simply weren’t enough of them to consistently win Presidential or Congressional elections. Republicans have resorted to a multi-pronged attack to tilt the playing field in their direction. Gerrymandering. New forms of voter suppression. And wedge-issues, issues about which they mostly did not care, but which would attract voters whose interests the party otherwise did not represent. “God, gays, and guns.” And most reliably, abortion. But the issue most responsible for the sea change of the electorate, which has endured to the present day, was racist in nature.</p>

<p>The godfather of the new Republican Party, and forefather of MAGA, was Arizona Senator Barry Goldwater. During his time, the Republican brand of racism was often cloaked in euphemisms. In his 1964 Republican Convention acceptance speech, Goldwater famously said: “Extremism in the defense of liberty is no vice.” This statement, and support of so-called “states rights” were code for suppression of black Americans. White southerners took them as a clarion call to abandon the Democratic Party and its efforts at desegregation and equality. In turn, black voters flocked to the Democratic Party.</p>

<p>In 1968, Richard Nixon followed Goldwater’s lead. His “law and order” campaign was a thinly veiled call for racist policies. Unspoken but understood was that law enforcement would be used to lay low the burgeoning Civil Rights movement. This “southern strategy” succeeded, and was broadened by Ronald Reagan in the 1980s. By then, southern states were turning red. Reagan pushed the message, now in slightly less coded language, of <a href="https://www.salon.com/2015/09/27/ronald_reagans_welfare_queen_myth_how_the_gipper_kickstarted_the_war_on_the_working_poor/">welfare queens driving Cadillacs</a>, at the cost of hard-working, tax-paying, and implicitly, white Americans. The message resonated far beyond the South, and into bedroom communities of working class white Americans such as Seven Hills, Ohio, where Nazi war criminal John Demjanjuk lived openly for years. These so-called “Reagan Democrats” fled the Democratic Party, despite its support of labor unions, and have never returned. The pull of racism was, and is, greater than their own self-interests.</p>

<p>And it wasn’t just labor unions that suffered. Support and funding for many public goods and services quickly evaporated after the passage of the Civil Rights Act. Public pools, once common in the thousands across the country, were <a href="https://www.melaninbasecamp.com/trip-reports/2024/2/26/third-places-that-disappeared-due-to-racism-public-pools">drained and filled with concrete</a> once the law required cities to grant admission to black patrons. Support for social welfare programs and safety nets similarly ran dry when Reagan made it abundantly clear that women of color would stand to benefit from these programs too. The desire for segregation was, and still is, so great among white conservatives that they opposed governmental programs that would benefit them, just to keep communities of color down.</p>

<p>When Barack Obama was elected President in 2008, to some <a href="https://www.politico.com/story/2009/08/what-happened-to-post-racial-america-025890">it appeared for a moment that we had moved on to a post-racial society</a>. But the backlash was swift. A virulent strain of racism took root in a grass-roots movement ultimately known as the Tea Party. At first it was difficult to take the group seriously, with its “Keep the Government out of my Medicare” signs. But its impact on the country was formidable. Just ask John Boehner and Paul Ryan. The Tea Party hijacked the Republican Party, making it virtually impossible for it to govern. If not the mother of the MAGA movement, the Tea Party was surely its wet nurse.</p>

<p>Donald Trump, he of no firm beliefs other than his own enrichment and aggrandizement, tapped into this rich vein of racial intolerance and white grievance. Today, there no longer is any subtlety in the messaging. The racism is right on the surface. White Supremacists form Trump’s own personal militia, waiting for his next marching orders. The transition from the Party of Lincoln to the Party of Rockefeller and ultimately to the Party of Trump is now complete.</p>

<p>Despite the specter of inflation and economic stagnation, and notwithstanding anecdotal evidence to the contrary, <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/11/22/nx-s1-5199119/2024-election-exit-polls-demographics-black-latino-voters">black Americans still voted overwhelmingly for Kamala Harris</a> and other Democratic candidates in 2024. On the other side of the aisle, Republicans will continue to stoke the flames of hatred and racism. But in the long run, the Republican strategy cannot prevail. Demographics are destiny. African American voters have <a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/codeswitch/2014/07/14/331298996/why-did-black-voters-flee-the-republican-party-in-the-1960s">increased from 12% to 14% of the electorate</a> in the past 20 years. That figure is likely to grow. Coupled with additional large increases in other communities of color in the country, America will become a majority-minority nation within this generation. True, the wall-building, deporter-in-chief made almost inexplicable inroads with the Hispanic community in 2024. But his policies are anathema to non-white voters to such an extent that it is difficult to believe their support will be durable. The true genius of the MAGA movement and its precursors has been to convince citizens to vote against their own best interests, which for low-to-moderate income Americans, are unquestionably championed by the Democratic Party. Rather despicably, Republicans have learned how to feed insecurities and hate to win votes. The not-so-subtle message of Trump and the Republicans is that they will bring back the middle class, but just for white people. Social Security, but without black people. Healthcare, but this time no DEI (their new dog-whistle for people of color). But of course, this promise is also beneficial to Republican politicians and oligarchs because it distracts from the class struggle they have no intention of addressing. As we are already seeing in 2025, Republicans have proceeded to govern for the benefit of the privileged few. The only way to combat the Republican con game is to relentlessly highlight the real harm Republican policies cause for most Americans, and the morally repugnant motivations behind their supremacist goals. At some point, hatred will be less important than personal suffering and our innate and human desire for fairness. If democracy can just survive until that day.</p>]]></content><author><name>Jekyll Esq</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The MAGA movement remains stubbornly resistant to definition or characterization. Other than cult-like fealty to its leader, Donald Trump, the movement appears to have no consistent, unifying principles. It is isolationist, but open to invading Canada, Mexico, Panama, and, for goodness sake, Greenland. Many of its adherents are Evangelical Christians, and yet they have deified a relentlessly corrupt and immoral sociopath as their Orange Jesus. The movement aspires to a type of rugged individualism, but has no problem jettisoning democracy for autocracy. Its roots are rural, but it is fine with the imposition of tariffs which will decimate the American farmer. MAGA fears and distrusts big tech, and yet its new oligarchy is comprised of Musk, Bezos, Zuckerberg and other tech bros. And it celebrates anti-elitism, while worshipping a leader who literally shits on a toilet made of gold.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Who We Are</title><link href="https://www.speakoutnews.com/2025/01/23/who-we-are.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Who We Are" /><published>2025-01-23T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2025-01-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://www.speakoutnews.com/2025/01/23/who-we-are</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.speakoutnews.com/2025/01/23/who-we-are.html"><![CDATA[<p>Faced with the ever rising presence of oligarchy, fascism, classism, racism, sexism, queerphobia, xenophobia, and a whole lot more, a baby boomer lawyer/political activist and a millennial scientist have decided to dab their pens in ink as dark as ages past, and yet somehow still present, to speak truth to power.  Jekyll Esq, the tempered liberal, and Mx Hyde, the radical leftist, are not afraid to call out injustice and the politicians who promote it.</p>

<p><em>Speak Out</em> is dedicated to shining a light on all the ways Trump, Republicans, MAGA, conservatives, reactionaries, and white supremacists are harming our siblings and comrades, the vulnerable and the disempowered, and even themselves, as they rush towards a fascist America.  In our thoughtful, well-researched articles, we will expose the harms and deeply flawed motivations behind these terrible ideologies, while also presenting our ideas for a truly just and fair society.</p>

<p>Why the aliases?  In the debate over the US Constitution, the Founding Fathers frequently published arguments using pseudonyms.  <a href="https://csac.history.wisc.edu/2022/07/22/pseudonyms-and-the-debate-over-the-constitution/">According to the <em>Center for the Study of the American Constitution</em> at the University of Wisconsin-Madison</a>, they did so for a number of reasons:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>First and foremost, it was felt that the avoidance of authors’ names concentrated attention on the issues, not on the personalities of the authors. Anonymity also contributed to the freedom of the press in that proponents of unpopular positions might be ostracized socially and/or economically if their identities were publicly divulged.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>Furthermore, during a time when dueling was not uncommon, writers were reluctant to acknowledge their authorship of harsh or abusive rhetoric might produce a duel.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>While we like to think our motivation is the first reason, in the age of the internet, and in the frightening moment we find ourselves, we would be foolish to discount the second.  And avoiding duels never goes out of fashion.</p>

<p>You can join us by reading our semi-regular posts at <a href="https://www.speakoutnews.com">speakoutnews.com</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Contact Us</name><email>speakoutnewsroom@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Faced with the ever rising presence of oligarchy, fascism, classism, racism, sexism, queerphobia, xenophobia, and a whole lot more, a baby boomer lawyer/political activist and a millennial scientist have decided to dab their pens in ink as dark as ages past, and yet somehow still present, to speak truth to power. Jekyll Esq, the tempered liberal, and Mx Hyde, the radical leftist, are not afraid to call out injustice and the politicians who promote it.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mission Statement</title><link href="https://www.speakoutnews.com/2025/01/23/mission-statement.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mission Statement" /><published>2025-01-23T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2025-01-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://www.speakoutnews.com/2025/01/23/mission-statement</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.speakoutnews.com/2025/01/23/mission-statement.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are here to speak truth to power and hold politicians accountable for their actions and policies.  We seek true justice, equality, and love.</p>]]></content><author><name>Contact Us</name><email>speakoutnewsroom@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are here to speak truth to power and hold politicians accountable for their actions and policies. We seek true justice, equality, and love.]]></summary></entry></feed>