<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.speakoutnews.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.speakoutnews.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-02-01T11:57:38-06:00</updated><id>https://www.speakoutnews.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Speak Out</title><subtitle>We are here to speak truth to power and hold politicians accountable for their actions and policies. We seek true justice, equality, and love.</subtitle><author><name>Contact Us</name><email>speakoutnewsroom@gmail.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Mission Statement</title><link href="https://www.speakoutnews.com/2025/01/23/mission-statement.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mission Statement" /><published>2025-01-23T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2025-01-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://www.speakoutnews.com/2025/01/23/mission-statement</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.speakoutnews.com/2025/01/23/mission-statement.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are here to speak truth to power and hold politicians accountable for their actions and policies.  We seek true justice, equality, and love.</p>]]></content><author><name>Contact Us</name><email>speakoutnewsroom@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are here to speak truth to power and hold politicians accountable for their actions and policies. We seek true justice, equality, and love.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Who We Are</title><link href="https://www.speakoutnews.com/2025/01/23/who-we-are.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Who We Are" /><published>2025-01-23T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2025-01-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://www.speakoutnews.com/2025/01/23/who-we-are</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.speakoutnews.com/2025/01/23/who-we-are.html"><![CDATA[<p>Faced with the ever rising presence of oligarchy, fascism, classism, racism, sexism, queerphobia, xenophobia, and a whole lot more, a Gen-X lawyer and millennial scientist have decided to dab their pens in ink as dark as ages past, and yet somehow still present, to speak truth to power.  Jekyll, Esq, the tempered liberal, and Mx Hyde, the radical leftist, are not afraid to call out the politicians with all the -isms and -ists they deserve.</p>

<p><em>Speak Out</em> is dedicated to shining a light on all the ways Trump, Republicans, MAGA, conservatives, reactionaries, and white supremacists are harming our siblings and comrades, the vulnerable and the disempowered, and even themselves, as they rush towards a fascist America.  In our thoughtful, well-researched articles, we will expose the harms and deeply flawed motivations behind these terrible ideologies, while also presenting our ideas for a truly just and fair society.</p>

<p>You can join us by reading our semi-regular posts at <a href="https://www.speakoutnews.com">speakoutnews.com</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Contact Us</name><email>speakoutnewsroom@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Faced with the ever rising presence of oligarchy, fascism, classism, racism, sexism, queerphobia, xenophobia, and a whole lot more, a Gen-X lawyer and millennial scientist have decided to dab their pens in ink as dark as ages past, and yet somehow still present, to speak truth to power. Jekyll, Esq, the tempered liberal, and Mx Hyde, the radical leftist, are not afraid to call out the politicians with all the -isms and -ists they deserve.]]></summary></entry></feed>